杰森:自从我们离开机场你就一直傻笑.来吧,
Jason: You've had that silly grin on your face ever since we left the airport.
告诉我是什么好消息?
Come on, when do I get to hear the news?
麦琪:你怎么知道我有好消息?
Maggie: What makes you think I've got news?
杰森:噢,我知道那种表情,
Jason: Oh, I know that look Maggie.
麦琪.
Either, you've got some good news or you just saw Hari Krishna getting
要么是你有好消息,要么就是你看见了什么有意思的事.
his robe caught in the baggage carousel.
麦琪:也许是的,也许不是.
Maggie: Maybe I do, maybe I don't.
杰森:噢,你喜欢逗我玩是吗?
Jason: Oh you love teasing me don't you?
麦琪:我没逗你.我知道一些你不知道的事情.
Maggie: I am not teasing you.I know something you don't know.
杰森:我猜就是霍华德参议员的采访成功了.
Jason: So I take it the story on Senator Howard went well.
麦琪:啊哈.
Maggie: Uh-huh.
杰森:而且你得到了很多专栏的好材料,还有….
Jason: And you got lots of good material for your column, and....
麦琪:还有什么?
Maggie: So what's new?
杰森:要么你告诉我,要么我就把车反车道上去.
Jason: Either you talk or I am going to turn this car into oncoming traffic.
麦琪:好吧,我不仅写了一篇漂亮的报道,
Maggie: Ok, not only did I get a great interview for the paper,
还给霍华德参议员留下了深刻的印象.
but Senator Howard was very impressed with me.
杰森:别卖关子了,麦琪.说吧.
Jason: There is a Simi approaching Maggie, spill it.
麦琪:参议院给了我一项工作.
Maggie: The Senator offered me a job.
杰森:什么?!?!
Jason: What?!?!
麦琪:媒体关系执行主任.
Maggie: Executive director of media relations.
杰森:噢,这太棒了!
Jason: Oh, well that's fantastic!
麦琪:而且薪水很高.
Maggie: With a great salary.
杰森:耶!
Jason: Yeah!
麦琪:是的,只是有一点小麻烦.
Maggie: Yes, there is only one small catch.
杰森:什么?没有停车位吗?
Jason: What?No parking space?
麦琪:噢,有的,上面还有我的名字呢.但是是在华盛顿特区.
Maggie: Oh, yes, with my name on it.But it's in Washington DC.
杰森:啊!
Jason: Ah!
麦琪:你不知道参议员给我这份工作时我有多满足.你知道别人在你膝边求你的感觉吗?
Maggie: I can't tell you what an ego boost it was to have the Senator
insist I take this job.
Do you know what its like to have someone begging at your knees?
杰森:哦,只有迈克要油钱的时候.
Jason: Well, just when Mike needs gas money.
麦琪:而且人选物色委员会已经不在找其他候选人了.
Maggie: And the executive search committee has stopped looking for any other candidates
杰森:他们可真会讨你欢心啊,亲爱的.
Jason: Honey that is very flattering, I guess you really suppressed them.
我猜你一定把他们迷住了.我是说没有多少女人走出参议员办公室的时候会说不的.
I mean it's not many women walk out of a Senators office saying no.
我真想看看当时那个糟老头脸上的表情.
I would have loved to have seen the look on that cranky old geezers face.
麦琪:杰森,霍华德参议员是个女人.
Maggie: Jason, Senator Howard is a woman.
杰森:噢!这解释了他在夜线上带的那些珍珠.
Jason: Oh!Well that explains the pearls he wore on nightline.
那么当你拒绝她时她有什么反应?
So how did she take it when you turned her down?
麦琪:啊,实际上…
Maggie: Well, actually...
杰森:你拒绝她了,麦琪?
Jason: You did turn her down Maggie?
麦琪:我心里想说"不",
Maggie: There was a "No" in my heart,
但嘴里却蹦出了"我会考虑的".
but "I'll think about it" came out of my mouth.
杰森:为什么蹦出来的不是"不行,我的家人都住在纽约"?
Jason: Why didn't "No, my family lives in New York" come out?
麦琪:杰森,
Maggie: Well Jason what was I suppose to say?
那是我该说的吗?对不起,
Sorry, I can't help you chart the world's go-political future;
我不能帮你设计世界的政治未来;里有一个猪肉节.
there is a pork festival at the Piggly-Wiggly.
杰森:干脆点,"算了吧,参议员"就可以了.
Jason: Simple, "Stuff it Senator" would suffice.
麦琪:噢,是吗?
Maggie: Oh really?And would you have said stuff it if you had been offered
如果是你得到了最理想的工作机会,你会说算了吧吗?
the perfect job?
杰森:岛人队已经有守门员了.
Jason: The Islanders already have a goalie.
麦琪:噢!杰森,我是认真的.
Maggie: Oh!Jason I'm serious.
杰森:好吧,麦琪.如果那意味着丈夫失业,孩子们失学,是的,当然,我必须说不.
Jason: Well Maggie, if it meant un-employing my spouse and uprooting my children, yes of course, I would have to say no.
麦琪:好吧,
Maggie: Well obviously I'm turning it down.
很明显我会拒绝的.但你就不能让我至少幻想一下,
But you could have at least let me revel in the fantasy for a minute,
再把那些该死的衣架收回去吗.
before tightening down the guilt screws.
杰森:对不起,我们来幻想吧.
Jason: I'm sorry, let's revel.
麦琪:现在我没心情了.
Maggie: Now I don't feel like it.
杰森:来吧,麦琪,求你了,现在我真的想听听细节了.
Jason: Come on Maggie, please, I am begging for details now.
麦琪:哦,那真叫人心动.我将有一个20人的团队.
Maggie: Well it is kind of impressive.I would have had a staff of twenty people.
杰森:哇!
Jason: Wow!
麦琪:我将可以在国会做证,
Maggie: I would have been testifying before congress and lobbying for
为消费者权利进行演说.
consumer rights.
杰森:你,在国会?
Jason: You in congress?
麦琪:是的,
Maggie: Yes, I would have had a major voice in shaping legislation.
在立法中我会有很大的发言权.实际上,
I actually would have had more to say in running this government then
我在如何管理政府方面的发言权甚至超过了玛莉莲.
Marilyn Quail.
杰森:没想到会有这么大的权力.
Jason: I had no idea it was this big.
麦琪:噢,亲爱的.
Maggie: Oh honey, it's the perfect blend of journalism and rights advocacy.
这是新闻和政治的完美结合点.我理想中的工作就是这样的.
It's everything I have ever wanted in a job.
噢,宝贝,
Oh boy, I just realized the longer I put off turning this down the sadder
我刚刚意识到我越晚拒绝它我就越难受.我现在就要给参议员打电话.
I'll be.I'll call the Senator right now.
杰森:麦琪,你不能拒绝这份工作.
Jason: Maggie you can't turn this job down.
麦琪:现在又轮到你瞎想了.
Maggie: Now you revel.
杰森:亲爱的,我是认真的.
Jason: Honey I'm serious, I'm deadly serious.
我非常认真.这份工作太好了,你不能拒绝.
This job is just too good for you to refuse.
麦琪:杰森,困难太多了.
Maggie: Jason this is nuts.
杰森:等一下,
Jason: Well wait a minute,
这么多年来我们一直在照顾孩子们,
we have been taking care of the kids all these years,
我们不是说过要为自己做些事情了吗?
haven't we always said we needed to do something for ourselves?
麦琪:我一直以为你说的是里的那些话呢.
Maggie: Well I always assumed you meant his and her massages at Mr.Steve's.
杰森:麦琪,考虑考虑.
Jason: Maggie, think about this.
麦琪:杰森,你的工作怎么办?
Maggie: Jason what about your practice?
杰森:我早就想做一些诊所的工作.
Jason: Well I have wanted to do some clinical work.
华盛顿有很多大诊所.麦琪,
There are great clinics in Washington.
这可能也是我更进一步的机会.
Maggie, maybe its time that I shook my life up a little bit too.
麦琪:但是孩子们转学的事怎么办呢?
Maggie: But what about yanking the kids out of school?
杰森:开萝尔成年了,迈克也21岁了.
Jason: Carol is an adult, Mike is over twenty-one.
麦琪:那么本和克莉丝呢?
Maggie: Well what about Ben and Chrissy?
杰森:亲爱的,他们很可爱.
Jason: Honey they are cute, somebody will take then in.
会有人收留他们的.亲爱的,这可能也是他们的好机会.
Honey, this could be a great opportunity for them.
麦琪:你是说收拾好东西就走?
Maggie: You mean just pick up and move?
杰森:啊,我还得和大家商量商量.
Jason: Well we will discuss it with the whole family.
麦琪:噢,杰森!
Maggie: Oh Jason!
杰森:我刚刚想到了另一种好处.
Jason: I just thought of another fringe benefit.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森:如果你进入,我就能看见琼·伦敦.
Jason: If you get on Good Morning America I could meet Joan London.
麦琪:噢!
Maggie: Oh!
克莉斯:西沃峰会到底是什么意思?
Chrissy: What is a Seaver summit anyway?
迈克:就是个晚餐欺骗者重要的家庭会议.
Mike: Well it's a supper duper important family meeting.
开萝尔:重要的让我错过了有派特·布查那和佩维·赫尔曼主演的了.
Carol: Presumably important enough to make us miss Cross Fire with Pat Buchanan and Pewee Herman.
本:重要到我一生只开过两次.最近一次是告诉我们你要出生了.
Ben: So important that we have only had two in my lifetime.The last one was to tell us you were going to be born.
迈克:是的,
Mike: Yeah, and the other was when you got caught singing "I'm looking
那一次是你被发现在午睡时唱"我在一个两条腿的奇迹下观望".
under a two legged wonder" during nap time.
杰森:好吧,大家都到齐了,很好.
Jason: All right, glad you're all here.
开萝尔:这应该很好.
Carol: This had better be good.
麦琪:噢,是的,至少我们希望你们都这么想.
Maggie: Oh it is, at least we hope you all think it is.
本:噢,上帝啊!你又要生孩子了.
Ben: Oh my God!You're going to have another baby.
杰森和麦琪:不,不!
Jason and Maggie: No, no!
杰森:但是你妈妈确实有个振奋人心的消息要跟你们分享.
Jason: But your mom does have some exciting news she'd like to share with you.
克莉斯:我们终于要养狗了?
Chrissy: We are finally getting a dog?
麦琪:不,我们要搬家了.
Maggie: No, we are moving.
迈克:我们要怎么?
Mike: We are what?
本:没门!
Ben: No way!
开萝尔:别开玩笑了!
Carol: No kidding!
克莉斯:不是狗?
Chrissy: No dog?
麦琪:我是说,我们可能会般,如果你们大家…
Maggie: I mean, we might move, that is if you all...
杰森:麦琪,慢慢来,从头讲.
Jason: Maggie why don't you just back and start at page one.
麦琪:大家坐下.
Maggie: Everybody sit down.
你们都知道我一直在做霍华德参议员的一系列专访.
You all know I have been doing a series of interviews with Senator Howard.
迈克:是的,不就是那个在节目里带珍珠项链的老头吗?
Mike: Yeah, isn't he that guy who wore pearls on Night Line?
麦琪:霍华德参议员是女的.
Maggie: Senator Howard is a woman.
迈克:不可能吧.
Mike: Get out of town.
麦琪:昨天她给了我一份媒体关系执行主任的工作.
Maggie: And yesterday she offered me a job as executive director of media
而那意味着我们要搬家去华盛顿.
relations.That means moving the family to Washington DC.
本:太糟糕了,听起来就让人不舒服.我要去臭臭家了.
Ben: To bad, sounded like a great gig.Well I'm off to Stinky's.
杰森:噢…本,本,西沃峰会还没结束呢.
Jason: Woo...Ben, Ben, the Seaver summate is far from over.
本:她是你的女人,爸爸,你管管她吧.
Ben: She is your woman dad, you straighten her out.
杰森:坐下,否则罚款.
Jason: Sit of pay rent.
克莉丝:我不明白,到底怎么了.
Chrissy: I don't understand what's going on here.
麦琪:亲爱的,妈妈在考虑接受一份新的工作.
Maggie: Well honey, mommy is thinking about getting a new job.
克莉丝:那你就不再是我的妈妈了吗?
Chrissy: You're not going to be my mommy any more?
麦琪:不,甜心.
Maggie: No sweetheart, I will always be your mommy.
我永远是你的妈妈.但是我们在考虑搬到一个叫华盛顿的好地方去.
But we are thinking about moving to a wonderful place called Washington DC.
克莉丝:美国的犯罪之都吗?我听广播上这么说的.
Chrissy: The murder capital of the USA?That's what I heard on hard copy.
杰森:显然,接下来的几天我们还有很多问题,
Jason: Well obviously we have a lot of questions to ask,
很多想法要讨论.
a lot of thinks to talk about over the next couple of days.
迈克:噢,孩子,那意味着还会有更多无聊的叽叽喳喳直到妈妈最后恢复理智.
Mike: Oh Boy, that means a lot more boring chit-chat until mom finally comes to her senses.
麦琪:迈克!
Maggie: Mike!
开萝尔:迈克,我真的不喜欢你对妈妈职业的挑剔态度.
Carol: Mike I really don't appreciate your caviler attitude towards mom's career.
迈克:是的,这就是你和我之间的区别.
Mike: Yeah, well, that's the difference between you and me.
开萝尔:是的,我懂挑剔的意思.
Carol: Yeah, I know what caviler means.
克莉丝:开萝尔,妈妈为什么要换新工作呢?
Chrissy: Carol, why does mommy want a new job?
开萝尔:啊,因为这是个好机会.
Carol: Well, because it is a great opportunity.
克莉丝:为什么?
Chrissy: why?
开萝尔:她会拥有大部分女性只能在梦中得到的那种工作.
Carol: Well she will have the kind of job that most women only dream of.
克莉丝:为什么?
Chrissy: Why?
开萝尔:克莉丝,我将不以姐姐的身份跟你说话,而是以"姐妹"的身份.
Carol: Chrissy, I am going to speak to you not as a sister, but as a "sister".
克莉丝:好的.
Chrissy: Ok.
开萝尔:现在,你可能已经注意到了,
Carol: Now, as you may have noticed,
我们生活在一个男性主导的社会,妇女只是附属.
we live in a male dominated society where in women are mere chattel.
我们的母亲,"我们的姐妹"现在得到了少有的摆脱男性束缚的机会.
Our mother, "our sister" has the rare opportunity to shrug off the yoke
你能跟上我吗?
of male oppression.Are you with me so far?
克莉丝:你知道你在说男字时鼻孔动了吗.
Chrissy: Did you know your nostrils move when you say the letter "M".
开萝尔:对不起,克莉丝;我想我刚才是在你头的上方说话的.
Carol: I'm sorry Chrissy; I think I was speaking over your head.
克莉丝:没关系;去华盛顿的路上你可以给我结实妈妈是怎么变成我的"姐妹"的.
Chrissy: It's ok; when we drive to Washington you can explain how mommy
is my "sister".
开萝尔:亲爱的,如果我们搬家去华盛顿,我是不会去的.
Carol: Sweetheart, if we move to Washington, I'm not going.
克莉丝:你不去?
Chrissy: Your not?
开萝尔:是的,不去.我要呆在哥伦比亚特区,住在宿舍里.这样我就离德怀特更近了.
Carol: Well no, I'm going to stay at Columbia and live in the dorms.And that way I can be closer to Dwight.
克莉丝:这样你感觉幸福吗?
Chrissy: And you're happy about that?
开萝尔:是的,当然.
Carol: Well of course I am.
克莉丝:那意味着我将再也看不到你了.
Chrissy: That means I'll never see you again.
开萝尔:你当然能,我们是一家人,家人会保持联系的,这是法律.
Carol: Sure you will, we are family and family stays in touch, it's the law.
克莉丝:是吗?
Chrissy: It is?
开萝尔:啊哈.我会经常去看你到时你就会讨厌我这张脸了.
Carol: Um-huh.I'm going to be visiting so much you are going to get tired of looking at this face.
克莉丝:噢,就像本和迈克那样.
Chrissy: Oh, like the way Ben and Mike do.
开萝尔:不,不会像本和迈克那样.
Carol: No, not like the way Ben and Mike do.
不管怎样,我们会一直很亲密的.
But no matter what, we will always be close.
克莉丝:拉钩保证?
Chrissy: Pinky swear?
开萝尔:拥抱保证.
Carol: Hug swear.
克莉丝:我爱你.
Chrissy: I love you.
开萝尔:我也爱你.
Carol: I love you.
麦琪:开萝尔,你太好了.
Maggie: Carol that was really sweet.
开萝尔:妈妈,别天真了.
Carol: Mom, snap out of it, I was talking to a kid.
我在哄她呢.真相会吓着她的.
The truth would have warped her.
麦琪:真相?
Maggie: The truth?
开萝尔:噢,一开始我们肯定会经常见面,
Carol: Oh sure we will see a lot of each other in the beginning,
但是不久就会只有到感恩节和圣诞节才能见一面.
but before long it will just be Thanksgiving and Christmas.
而在你还没有明白过来的时候,我们的丈夫就会连假期也不往来了.
And before you know it our spouses won't want to come over on the holidays.
再后来就会用传真机发张情人卡说,对不起,我忘了你的生日.
And before long we will be faxing Valentines and sending cards that say sorry I forgot your birthday.
麦琪:开萝尔,我们的生日在同一个月.
Maggie: Carol, our birthdays are in the same month.
开萝尔:这会让情况更加悲观.
Carol: Which only makes it all the more tragic.
麦琪:是啊,我们真的不会有多少在一起的时间了.
Maggie: Well we really won't have as much time to spend together.
麦琪:现在轮到你说个秘密了.
Maggie: Now it's your turn to share a secret.
开萝尔:好吧.还记得上个月有个周六的晚上,
Carol: All right.Remember the Saturday night last month when Debbie, Shelly,
戴比,雪莉和我一起去图书馆,然后在戴比家过夜吗?
and I went to the library and then we spent the night at Debbie's house?
麦琪:是的.
Maggie: Yeah.
开萝尔:其实我们根本就没学习.
Carol: Well we didn't study at all.
麦琪:是的.
Maggie: Yeah.
开萝尔:相反,我们坐上去曼哈顿的火车,到一家很棒的俱乐部跳舞.
Carol: Instead, we took the train into Manhattan and went to this really neat dance club in Soho.
麦琪:是吗?
Maggie: Yeah?
开萝尔:那里只有年龄超过21岁的人才能进去,所以戴比和雪莉都要放弃了.
Carol: You had to be twenty-one to get into this place so Debbie and Shelly
但我很聪明,我贿赂了门卫.
were about to give up.But I was so cool, I greased the doorman.
麦琪:贿赂?
Maggie: Greased?
开萝尔:我给了他20美圆就放我们进去了.
Carol: I slipped him twenty dollars to let us in.
我是说是不是很棒?
I mean is that neat or what?
那晚真好,我们和几个甚至不会说英语的家伙跳到了凌晨4点.
It was so great,
we danced till four in the morning with these guys who didn't even speak
English.
然后我们坐车回来,一头扎进她的房间,
And then we took the train back and snuck into her room and were sound
在她父母醒来前呼呼大睡.
asleep before her parents ever woke up.
这一天里,没人比我更聪明.
And to this day, no one is any the wiser.
麦琪:我会怀念这次谈心的.开萝尔,
Maggie: I'm going to miss our heart to heart talks.
也许我疯了才会想要搬家.
Carol, maybe I am crazy to even consider moving the family.
开萝尔:噢,别这样妈妈,
Carol: Oh, come-on mom I admire you.
我崇拜你.
I mean there are very few women who are willing to deny their families
我是说很少有女人能拒绝家人的要求,只考虑她们自己.
needs and think only of themselves.
麦琪:噢,杰森.
Maggie: Oh Jason, the more I think about this move the more I question
我越想这次搬家,我就越怀疑是否应该接受这份工作.
whether taking this job is right.
杰森:当然应该.
Jason: Of course it is.
麦琪:那你怎么看我们搅乱孩子们的生活呢?
Maggie: Well how can you say that when we will be upsetting our children's lives?
杰森:孩子们喜欢这样,我们也得考虑自己.
Jason: Our children love to be upset, about time we got even.
我没有别的意思,
I don't mean to make light of this Maggie,
麦琪.只是改变对人有好处.
it's just that change is good for people.
它使人坚强.
It makes them stronger.
麦琪:或者造成伤害.
Maggie: Or scars them for life.
还记得那次我动了客厅的家具吗?
Remember the time I rearranged the living room furniture?
本做了一星期的恶梦.
Ben had nightmares for a week.
杰森:更别提他摔的青一块紫一块的腿了.
Jason: Not to mention black and blue legs.
孩子们以前离开过家,麦琪,
Our kids have been uprooted before Maggie,
还记得那个周末我们都在迈克家过的吗?
remember that weekend we all had to spend at Mike's?
本:我在这地板上睡不着,有东西在我身上爬.
Ben: I can't sleep on this floor, things are crawling on me.
麦琪:噢,对不起,亲爱的,
Maggie: Oh, I'm sorry honey, just climb in.Carol.
上来吧.开萝尔:等一下,
Wait a second, the snot ball gets a bed and I have to suffer on the
那个混球都在床上睡,而我却要在地板上忍.凭什么!
floor.Forget it!
迈克:嘿,等一等.哦,抓住,时间到.我是床的主人,而你们却都睡了上去.
Mike: Hey wait a minute, wooo, hold on, time out.I'm the one who owns
the bed and you guys are going to sleep in it
我就该睡地板吗?没门!让开点.
I'm suppose to sleep on the floor?No way!Make room.
杰森:噢!
Jason: Oh!
开萝尔:嘿,迈克,我的脚!
Carol: Hey Mike that's my foot!
杰森:谁的胳膊顶着我的后背呢?
Jason: Well who has got their elbow in my back?
麦琪:伙计们,我的脚趾甲!
Maggie: Guys my toenails!
杰森:这张床上睡不下这么多人!
Jason: You can't have this many people in this bed!
迈克:爸爸,这宝贝上睡过比这还多两倍的人.别担心.这里都是男人.你知道我的意思.
Mike: Dad I have had twice this many people in this baby.Don't worry they were all guys.You know what I mean.
开萝尔:等等,本,你尿床了吗?
Carol: Wait Ben, did you wet the bed?
本:没有!等一下,我们都没有尿床,是床把我们弄湿了.
Ben: No!Wait a minute, we are not all wetting the bed, the bed is
wetting us
开萝尔:我只想指出是迈克把水床弄坏了!
Carol: I just want to point out that it was Mike who broke the waterbeds back!
杰森:噢,闭嘴!!
Jason: Oh shut up!!
麦琪:噢,很好,
Maggie: Oh nice, the genius who canceled his credit card tells his daughter
注销自己信用卡的天才父亲在让她的女儿"闭嘴"?!
to "shut up"?!
杰森:我做了我应该做的,而且我告诉你,老实呆在这里比向华尔特借钱强的多!
Jason: I did what I had to do, and I'm telling you staying here is a lot better then borrowing money from Walter!
麦琪:那是因为他不会借给你!
Maggie: That's because he wouldn't have lent it to you!
杰森:是吗?这说明你还有所不知,我根本没问过他!是的,你说对了!男人有尊严!
Jason: Oh yeah?Well that shows how much you know, I didn't even ask him!Yeah that's right!A man has pride!
麦琪:没人逼我们呆在这里,是你愿意的?!
Maggie: You we weren't forced to stay in this place, you chose this?!
杰森:没错,
Jason: That's right, I chose it!
我喜欢!
But that was before I so stupidly thought that we might enjoy this as
但是那是在我愚蠢的以为我们会把这作为小小的家庭乐趣来享受之前的事!!!
a little family fun!!!
哈,哈,哈!!!
Ha, ha, ha!!!
迈克:你们是准备一直站在那,还是帮我灌满我的床呢.
Mike: Are you all just going to stand there or are you going to help me drink my bed.
杰森:麦琪,除非你有很好的理由,
Jason: Maggie don't you dare turn this job down unless you have a real
你不会推掉这份工作吧.
good reason.
麦琪:这是个好工作.
Maggie: It is a great job.
杰森:啊哈.
Jason: um-huh.
杰森:相信我只要孩子们一适应搬家的想法,
Jason: Trust me the kids are going to be just fine once they get use to
他们就会好起来的.
the idea of moving.
麦琪:进来.
Maggie: Come in.
本:呃… 我就是来道声晚安.噢,恩,顺便说一句,你们可以去华盛顿但我不去.
Ben: Umm... guys I just wanted to say goodnight.Oh, um, by the way you
guys can go on ahead to Washington but I'm not going
麦琪:本!本,亲爱的,我们谈谈好吗?
Maggie: Ben!Ben, sweetheart can we talk about this?
本:有用吗?我是说,不管怎样,你不会听我的.
Ben: Why bother?I mean you won't listen to me, any way
麦琪:本杰明·胡博特·赫拉迪欧·亨弗雷·西沃,这不公平!
Maggie: Benjamin Huppert Horatio Humphrey Seaver, that's not fair!
本:如果生活公平的话,我的中名就应该是比尔.
Ben: If life were fair my middle name would be Bill.
妈妈,我讨厌这样.我是说迈克和开萝尔能自己拿主意.
Mom I hate this I mean Mike and Carol get to decide what they want.
你们却总是把我当小孩.
You guys treat me like I'm a little baby.
麦琪:我们没有.
Maggie: We do not.
本:你们有,有,就是有.
Ben: You do too, do too, do too.
麦琪:让我来吧,你会伤着自己的.
Maggie: Now here let me do this, you are going to hurt yourself.
本:你能把它切成四小块吗?
Ben: Could you cut it in four little solders for me?
麦琪:来吧,本,我知道你很不好受,但是我们能不能理智点看问题呢?
Maggie: Come on Ben, I know your upset but could we please look at this rationally?
本:好吧,我会理智的.
Ben: Ok, I will be rational.
你雇了个私家侦探在学校跟踪我,现在他已经把我的所有情况一五一十的告诉了你,
You have hired a private detective to follow me around school and now he has told you that I have finally shed my last vestiges of geek-ocity,
在一个长的像同性恋的女参议员的帮助下,现在你又要撕碎我的生活.
and now you have decided to smash my life into little pieces with the help of a woman senator who looks like Joe Peschie.
麦琪:行了,亲爱的,别扯远了.
Maggie: Come on honey, don't get carried away.
本:我!我从没扯远.
Ben: Me!I never get carried away.
本:你是什么意思?
Ben: What your point?
迈克:我认为他以前结过婚,
Mike: I think that if he was married before,
这很可能意味着他还有另一个妻子.
that probably means he had another wife.
本:噢,不!
Ben: Oh no!
迈克:而且如果他们在长岛的某处一起住着的话,
Mike: And I wouldn't be a bit surprised if they are living somewhere on
我一点也不会吃惊.
long island.
本:是的,爸爸不会愿意搬到远离孩子们的地方.
Ben: Yeah, dad wouldn't want to move far away from his kids.
开萝尔:什么孩子们?
Carol: What kids?
本:他每次说去理发时去看的那些.
Ben: The ones he goes and visits when he say's he is going to get a haircut.
开萝尔:本!
Carol: Ben!
本:我知道了,爸爸陪那些孩子玩的时候,
Ben: I got it,
他的妻子就给他理发.
dad's other wife cuts his hair while he plays with his other kids.
所以他们不会很远,我打赌就在这条街上.
So they couldn't be far away, I bet right on this street.
也许我们上学的时候他们就来这里.穿我们的衣服,
Maybe they come over here while we are at school.
玩我们的玩具.所以我的房间才这么乱.
Wear our clothes and play with our stuff.That's why my room gets so messed up.
本:好吧,我确实几乎从不扯远.看,妈妈,你不能等一等,比如说,我高中毕业以后再找个好工作吗?
Ben: All right, all right I almost never get carried away.Look mom, cant you wait to find a great job tell after I'm out of high school?
麦琪:噢,亲爱的,我也希望那样,可这是一辈子只有一次的机会.
Maggie: Oh sweetheart, I wish I could but this is a once in a lifetime chance.
现在我知道你的想法了;这对我们所有人来说都是一个很大的变化.
Now I know how you feel;
我也很担心.
this is going to be a big change for all of us.I'm worried too.
本:不及我一半担心.
Ben: Not half as much as I am.
麦琪:你一直很支持我啊.
Maggie: You have always been there for me.
麦琪:本,我知道这对我们所有人都是很大的改变.不能在这陪你让我很担心,
Maggie: Ben I know this has been a big change for all of us.
因为,啊,你是最小的.
And I worry about not being here for you because, well, you're the youngest.
同时,我也很担心开萝尔,
And I worry about not being here for Carol because she is a girl and she
因为她是女孩,需要母亲.
her mother.
不能在这还让我担心迈克,
And I worry about not being here for Mike to keep him from accidentally
因为他会偶尔打破东西.
blowing something up.
相信我;我担心留你爸爸一个人在这应付不了你们这些调皮鬼.
And believe me; I worry about leaving your father here all alone to cope
with all you monsters.
本:你不必担心,妈妈,你会把自己逼疯的.
Ben: You shouldn't worry so much mom, you will make yourself crazy.
麦琪:我爱你,小南瓜头.
Maggie: I love you little pumpkin-head.
麦琪:啊,南瓜头.
Maggie: Ah, pumpkin-head.
迈克:嘿,本.能借我10块钱吗?
Mike: Hey Ben, can I borrow ten bucks?
本:自己拿吧,最上面的抽屉,卷在我的"韦恩世界"衬衫里.
Ben: Help yourself, top drawer rolled up inside my Wayne's World underwear.
迈克:醒醒吧,本.我告诉过你多少次了,你从来不借钱给家人.兄弟,妈妈是对的,你的确很消沉.
Mike: Hello, earth to Ben.How many times have I told you, you never lend
money to family.Boy, moms' right you are depressed
本:再也不会了.我正要去问臭臭的家长,高中毕业后我能否和他们住一起.
Ben: Not anymore, I am just going to ask Stinky's parents if I can stay with them tell after high school.
迈克:啊,本.我才不信你会想和有臭味的人住在一起呢.
Mike: Uh, Ben I don't think you want to stay with the people who made Stinky.
本:好吧,那我就在学校图书馆睡.我敢肯定他们还留着你的床铺.
Ben: Fine then I will sleep in the school library.I'm sure they still have your cot set up.
迈克:本尼,好了.逍遥的日子没有指望的时候你看我难过了吗?
Mike: Benny, come on, do I look upset at the prospect of being tosses out of my cushy little bachelor pad?
没有,你知道为什么吗?那是不会发生的事.
No, and do you know why?Not going to happen.
本:什么?
Ben: What?
迈克:本,来吧,妈妈只是正经历更年期综合症而已.我是说,她只是需要想想改变.
Mike: Ben, come on, mom is just going through some kind of post-nasal mid
life crisis.I mean, she just wants to think about change
本:迈克,别傻了.妈妈不会就这么算了的.
Ben: Mike grow a beard.Mom wouldn't pull our chains for nothing.
迈克:好吧.那我们说,即使有百万分之一的可能,她真的经历这次工作的改变.你们也搬家到华盛顿了.
Mike: Ok, well let's just say in a million-to-one shot, she actually goes through with this whole job change and you move to Washington.
我知道你一定以为华盛顿到处都是低劣的骗子和疯狂的艺术家.但是,
Now I know you think Washington is probably filled with sleazy crooks
放松点;那还有多一个人的空间.
and con-artists.But relax; there is room for one more.
本:迈克,出去.
Ben: Mike leave my room.
迈克:本尼,看,
Mike: Benny, look, we would be talking about a whole new school,
我们说的是一所全新的学校,绝对没有人知道西沃大火的故事.
who knows absolutely nothing about the sure fire Seaver scams.
本:是的,我不知道.
Ben: Yeah, I don't know.
迈克:看,本尼,我是说如果他们真的带你去华盛顿,他们肯定会用一辆车什么的讨好你.
Mike: Look Benny, I mean if they were really going to drag you all the way to Washington they would have already tried to bribe you with a car of something.
本:一辆车,我要车有什么用?
Ben: A car, what would I do with a car?
迈克:现在记住了,当我说现在,你就踩油门.
Mike: Now remember, when I say now you pop the clutch.
本:说的好象我真的有了一样.
Ben: Like I said before I got it.
迈克:那是到时候的事,现在说现在的.
Mike: That was then this is now.
本:啊!!!
Ben: AHHH!!!
迈克:刹车,本尼,刹车.
Mike: The brake, Benny the break!
迈克的朋友:现在我们两个谁说话他也听不见了.
Mike's friend: He doesn't hear either one of us now.
本:噢,我还活着,我还活着,我还活着!嘿,这真有趣.
Ben: Oh, I'm alive, I'm alive, I'm alive, I'm alive!Hey, this is fun.
本:再过三年我也不是18岁.
Ben: And I am not going to be eighteen for another three years.
迈克:是的,但是再过6个月你就16岁了,而那是华盛顿法定驾车年龄.
Mike: Yeah, but in six months you will be sixteen and that's the legal driving age in DC.
杰森:我已经召集了所有的孩子,国会山小姐.也可以说全家已经集合完毕,他们正在等待你的国情咨文的演讲.
Jason: Well I have rounded up all the kids Miss Capital Hill.You could say the house is assembled and they're awaiting your state of the union address.
麦琪:杰森,这些华盛顿玩笑快让我发疯了,
Maggie: Jason these Washington puns are starting to get on my nerves,
别再说了好吗?
will you please stop?
杰森:全听你的,亲爱的.向你致敬.我知道这有点不严肃,但是,嘿,我对你接受这份工作感到很高兴.
Jason: Whatever you say dear.Hail to the chief.I know it's a little bit dorky but, hey, I'm excited about you taking this job.
麦琪:噢,亲爱的.我想了很多,本肯定不会支持这次搬家.我想可能没办法接受了.
Maggie: Oh honey, I have thought a lot about this and Ben is never going to warm up to this move.I just don't think I can go through with it.
杰森:亲爱的,这是一生难得的好机会啊.这对你来说相当的重要.
Jason: Honey, this is a chance of a lifetime, this thing means a lot to you.
麦琪:是的,或者说曾经是的.看,本再过3年就上大学了.为他想想吧.
Maggie: It does, or it did, Look, Ben is going to be in college in 3 years.Consider how about Ben.
杰森:可是到那时那个职位可能就有人了,麦琪,
Jason: Well, that position just may be filled by then Maggie,
或者克莉斯又不想让你去华盛顿了.
or maybe Chrissy won't want you to move to Washington.
等你最终下定决心追求梦想的时候,麦琪,
By the time you finally decide to follow your dream Maggie it's going
你就该退休了.
to be time to retire.
麦琪:亲爱的,
Maggie: Honey, you told me I shouldn't pass up on this opportunity unless
是你告诉我不能错过这次机会除非我有充分的理由.
I had a heck of a reason.
我想伤害孩子们中的任何一个已经足够充分了.
Well I just think that hurting one of my kids is reason enough.
杰森:好吧,如果你决定了,我支持你.
Jason: All right, if that's your decision, I support it.
本:妈妈,呃,
Ben: Mom, um, I've got to talk to you.
我有话要跟你说.在你做决定之前,我想你应该听听我的真实想法.
Before you make your decision I think you should hear how I really feel.
迈克:开萝尔,你在干吗?
Mike: Carol, what are you doing?
开萝尔:看看这个跟我的卧室配不配.我敢肯定如果我让她感到足够的内疚,
Carol: Seeing if this will fit in my dorm room.
她就会把它给我.
I'm sure mom will give it to me if I make her feel guilty enough.
迈克:开萝尔,妈妈哪也不去了.
Mike: Carol, mom is not going anywhere.
开萝尔:迈克,她不可能放弃这么好的工作.
Carol: Mike there is no way she could pass up a job like this.
迈克:开萝尔,告诉你,那不可能了.
Mike: Carol, I'm telling you, not going to happen.
麦琪:好吧,各位,我已经决定了.我要接受华盛顿的工作.
Maggie: Ok, everyone, I have made my decision.I am taking the job in Washington!
杰森:是吗?!
Jason: You are?!
麦琪:是的!
Maggie: Yeah!
本:而我将得到一辆车!
杰森:是吗?
00:21:35,400
Ben: And I'm getting a car! Jason: You are?